

Chaitanya Suvarna

Senior Developer

- k chaitanya-suvarna.github.io
- +91 8767223842

Profile

Experienced developer and a strong business development professional with a **Master's Degree** focused in **Computer Applications** from Sardar Patel Institute of Technology.

I am a logical thinker and like solving problems by leveraging technology. I have worked on and delivered services using Java and AWS, ETL solutions in AbInitio, REST-ful APIs and Microservices using .Net Core.

Being an autodidact, I'm always inquisitive about new technology and trying out various pet projects. I never shy away from opportunities in different technical landscapes.

Professional Experience

Amazon

07/2022 - present | Pune, India

Software Development Engineer 2

- Senior Developer in Zappos Catalog domain
- Coordinate with Product Manager and Business Teams to create solutions and High Level Designs
- Code reviews and Design reviews within the team and mentoring junior developers
- Designed, developed and delivered Java based services using AWS components to solve business problems in Amazon <-> Zappos Catalog space

Barclays

06/2021 - 07/2022 | Pune, India

Senior Developer

- Tech Lead for Barclays Partner Finances
- Creating LowLevel Designs that are scalable and maintainable by liaising with Product Owners and Stakeholders.
- Code reviews and mentoring junior developers with best coding practices.
- Creating common libraries/packages that can be used by other developers for common practices.
- Hands-on work in creation of RESTful APIs and microservices while following Test-Driven Development.
- Supporting PROD incident/issues and communicating with stakeholders relating to findings/RCA and resolution.

Barclays

07/2017 - 05/2021 | Pune, India

Developer

- .Net developer for Barclays Partner Finances, working on dotnet core APIs and **microservices** and SQL server.
- Developed and delivered **ETL Solutions** for Customer Data and Regulatory projects in Ab Initio.
- Developed and delivered **Web Application** in ASP.NET MVC/SQL Server and SSIS for FATCA/CRS Report generation.
- Engaged in **change management** and support in various phases of application lifecycle.
- Technologies worked on: dotnet core, EntityFamework core, NUnit, SpecFlow, TFS(CI/CD pipeline), SQL Server Integration services, SQL Server, ASP.NET, Powershell scripting, UNIX shell scripting, Ab Initio, ORACLE.

Intern Analyst

- Intern in Legal run the bank team where I provided support for applications used by the Legal team.
- As an intern I developed 2 projects that helped the Legal RTB team perform their support duties efficiently.
 - One-click Health Check of all services/Applications Created an executable using C# & Selenium which performed all the health check actions automatically and an Excel Workbook was generated with status report of all applications.
 - One Stop Shop Service Management

A web application developed with ASP.Net, Bootstrap and SQL Server which used 'Windows Management Instrumentation' to list down all storage/service status of servers being monitored, highlighting stopped services or storage thresholds. You could also start/stop services from the web application.

Credit Suisse

06/2016 - 07/2016 | Pune, India

Intern

- Intern in automation testing team, worked on test case automation using Selenium and Hexawise.
- Got to learn testing concepts like test coverage and how we could leverage these tools to save time and manual effort by automating regression packs etc.

Education

Sardar Patel Institute of Technology (Mumbai University)

07/2014 - 07/2017 | Mumbai, India

Master of Computer Applications

• Final CGPI: 8.21/10

Usha Pravin Gandhi College (Mumbai University)

07/2011 - 07/2014 | Mumbai, India

B.Sc. Information Technology

Final CGPA: 6.80/8

Skills

.Net Framework .Net Core, EntityFramework, ASP.Net, Windows

Services, NUnit, SpecFlow

AWS Cloud Components

Ab Initio Graph Development, Sandbox Setup, Multifile

Lambda, ECS, SQS, DynamoDB, S3

components, Web Components

SQL Server

Java

SQL Server 2014, SQL Server Integration Services

DDL and DML operations, PL\SQL

Spring Framework, Gradle, JUnit

. . . .

Agile/Scrum Dev Tools

. . . .

Python

Git, Jira, Rally

Django framework, Beautiful Soup

Publications

Efficient heart disease prediction system using optimization technique 🗗

08/02/2018

IEEE Xplore

This research paper focuses on developing a prediction algorithm with the help of data mining and an optimisation technique called Particle Swarm Optimisation technique. The results obtained show that Particle Swarm Data Mining Algorithms are competitive, not only with other evolutionary techniques but also with industry standard algorithms, and can be successfully applied to heart disease prediction.

Interests

Running

Sub 1 hour 10k finisher. Training for first half marathon.

Reading

topics: mystery, mythology, philosophy and history

Guitar

Was part of college music group, still continue playing as a hobby.

Calligraphy

A hobby that helps me calm down and collect my thoughts.

Tech/Gadgets ☑

Always tinkering with new technology and gadgets with pet projects

Kannada

Languages

English
Hindi
Marathi